KRISNA GUPTA

PhD Candidate in Economics at The Australian National University (ANU)

At Crawford School of Public policy under supervision of Arianto Patunru. My thesis is about the impact of trade and investment policies to Indonesian firms. I help tutor some courses in The ANU. I am also an associate researcher at CIPS Indonesia



EDUCATION

2014 • Universitas Indonesia

SELECTED RESEARCH AND PUBLICATIONS

Book

2014

• Gupta, Krisna and Enny Mardjono (2021). *Indonesia Emas Berkelanjutan 2045: Kumpulan Pemikiran Pelajar Indonesia Sedunia Seri 01 Ekonomi*. Jakarta: LIPI Press. ISBN: 978-602-496-208-1

Journal Article

- Gupta, Krisna. (2022). The Heterogenous Impact of Tariff and NTM on Total Factor Productivity of Indonesian Firms. *Bulletin of Indonesian Economic Studies*. DOI: 10.1080/00074918.2021.2016613
- Gupta, Krisna. (2021). The Importance of Financial Liberalisation for Economic Growth: The Case of Indonesia. *Bulletin of Indonesian Economic Studies*, 57:2, 175-201, DOI: 10.1080/00074918.2020.1747596

Book Chapter

• Gupta, Krisna. (2020). "Industri 4.0 Sebagai Solusi Daya Saing Industri Indonesia?". In Denny Irawan, Wasisto Raharjo Jati, Oscar Karnalim, Asrul Sidiq (ed.), *Mewujudkan Indonesia 4.0: Kumpulan Pemikiran Pelajar Indonesia di Australia*. Jakarta: Yayasan Pustaka Obor Indonesia. ISBN: 978-602-433-918-0

Policy Paper

• Gupta, Krisna, Deasy Pane and Donny Pasaribu. (2022). "The advent of a new trade governance after the Omnibus Law: Neraca Komoditas". *CIPS Policy Paper* no.47.

Book Review

 Gupta, Krisna. (2020). "World Trade Evolution: Growth, Productivity and Employment - edited by Lili Yan Ing and Miaojie Yu". Asian-Pacific Economic Literature. https://doi.org/DOI:10.1111/apel.12291

CONTACT INFO

krisna.or.id

For more information, please contact me via email.

SKILLS

Trained in economics with heavy use of various types of panel data regressions to evaluate policies

Have a long exposure with STATA, but recently learning R and Python for econometrics

Experience in running structural model (e.g. GTAP) using GEMPACK software

This resume was made with the R package **pagedown**.

Last updated on 2022-03-14.

Proceedings

Gupta, Krisna, Bayu Sutjiatmo and Muhammad Kurniawan. 2019.
"How Trump's steel and aluminium tariff shapes future world trade".
in Abdullah, Widiaty and Abdullah (eds). Global Competitiveness:
Business Transformation in the Digital Era. London: Routledge.

Popular Publications / Oped

- Gupta, Krisna and Deasy Pane. 2021. "Restrictive regulations on foreign trade may hurt economy". *The Jakarta Post.*
- Pasaribu, Donny and Krisna Gupta. 2020. "Will IA-CEPA be the boost to Australia-Indonesia relations leaders are banking on?". *Indonesia At Melbourne*.

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Lecturer

- Politeknik APP (home institution): Business Statistics (2016-2017)
- Universitas Petra: Intro to Economics (2020)

Tutor at Australian National University

- POLS3025 Contemporary Political Analysis, using STATA in political analyses (2017)
- ECON3101 Microeconomics 3 (2018-2021)
- ECON3102 Macroeconomics 3 (2021)
- ECON2102 Macroeconomics 2 (2019)
- EMET3008 Applied Macro and Financial Econometrics (2020)

Teaching Assistant (graduate) at Universitas Indonesia

- Macroeconomics 2 (2016)
- Microeconomics 2 (2015)

₽ PRIZES

2012 • VU Fellowship Programme (VUFP)

A scholarship given by VU for my master degree

Amsterdam, The Netherlands

2017 • Australia Awards Indonesia (AAI)

A scholarship from the Australian government to conduct a study in Australia.

• Canberra, Australia

2019 • Hadi Soesastro Prize (HSP)

Awarded by the Australian government to be used for research in Indonesian development

O Canberra, Australia